听着啊 我来告诉你
You see now, I'm here to tell you,
这种保持沉默的招数 其实根本没用
this remaining silent shit ain't nothing like they make it out to be.
你在这儿一言不发
You up in here all tight with it,
等着你雇佣的律师来
waiting for your paid lawyer,
自以为聪明了 对吧
thinking you all wise, ain't you?
错了 听着
No, see...
如果你只是幕后军师 这招还有用
that work when you some kind  of criminal mastermind...
可你是被目睹逃离案发现场
when you ain't been seen runnin' from the deed.
而且你那该死的同伙就在隔壁
When your own fuckin' running partner ain't in the next room,
要揭发你呢
putting you in.
哦嘢
Oh, yeah.
行啊
Yep.
他可是啥都招了 像个小婊子呢
He's telling it like a little bitch.
我们甚至还替他买麦当劳吃呢 因为他真是很帮得上忙啊
We even went to Mickey D's for him because he was so motherfucking helpful.
两客巨无霸 大份的薯条
Two quarter pounders, big fries,
还有麦乐园曲奇饼和胡椒博士哦 (一种焦糖碳酸饮料)
McDonaldland cookies, Dr. Pepper.
你们都好这个 对吧
That's how your boy roll, right?
好了 出来吧
All right. Step out.
要去哪儿
Where we going?
休息室 这样你可以好好吃 对吧
Break room. So you can enjoy that, huh?
好的 不过还是什么都不会说的
All right.  But I still ain't sayin' shit to you.
行
Yeah.
Marnell 你他妈干什么啊
Marnell, what the fuck?
咱一起唱这双簧多少年了啊
How many years you figure we've been doing the same shit?
至少20年了吧
20, at least.
真话
True.
假话 放到机里去吧
False. Load them up.
- 这破招还真管用吗 - 那还用说
- So, this shit actually works.  - Hell yeah.
美国人都是猪脑袋 别人说的俺们都信
Americans are stupid people. We believe what we're told.
好吧
All right.
这玩意能感觉我的心跳?
So, it can feel my heartbeat?
是把脉 是的
Pulse, yeah.
如果Marnell说是我拿的枪 那是他骗人
If Marnell say I had the gun, he lying.
这话由这机器说了算 小子
The machine tells the tale, son.
可以了吗 教授
Are we ready, Professor?
- 行了 - 从简单的开始
- Yeah.  - We'll start with an easy one.
你的真名是叫Dashawn Fredericks吗
Is your name, in fact, Dashawn Fredericks?
是
Yeah.
真话
True.
你真住在...
And do you reside, in fact,
巴尔的摩西区Woodyear街 1200街区吗
the 1200 block of Woodyear Street in West Baltimore?
是
Yeah.
- 真话 - 你跟Marnell...
- True.  - And did you and Marnell
就像Marnell说的那样 在Cary街射杀了你们的伙计Pookie吗
shoot your boy Pookie down on Cary Street just like Marnell said you did?
不 没有
No. No.
假话 你这撒谎的混蛋
Lie. You lying motherfucker.
机器从没错过 小子
Machine is never wrong, son.
操蛋
Fuck, man!
那黑鬼的嘴就是不严实
Nigger can't never keep his damn mouth shut.
我本该自己把Pookie给爆了
I should've busted a cap in Pookie ass my own self.
把Marnell留在家里才是
Left Marnell home and shit.
他真是个婊子 绝对的
He just a bitch, is all.
谎撒得越大 他们越信以为真
The bigger the lie, the more they believe.
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
Sync:龙骨 雪里玉@FRS
* Way down in the hole *
谎撒得越大 他们越信以为真    -Bunk
火线重案组 第五季 第1集
the.wire.s05e01
黑莓呢
Where's the BlackBerry?
他还带着mp3呢
He brought his tunes.
干这些活儿都是有工资的吧
All the running shit pay, don't it?
来了一个人 男性 身份不明  看到了吗 Jimmy?
We got one coming in. Unidentified number-one male. Got him, Jimmy?
嗯 脸对脸呢
Yeah. More face-to-face.
老天
Oh, man.
要是真能领到钱  干这活儿会更有意思
You know, this would be more fun if we were actually getting paid.
嗨 我在西区那会儿 听说过你的一个故事
Hey, you know, I heard a story about you, when I was back in the West.
都是没影儿的事
It's not true.
我还没说是什么事呢
I haven't even told it yet.
不管是什么 都是没影儿的
Whatever it is, it's not true.
有一次扫黄 你当卧底
You were on a vice undercover one time,
结果你没有收网 而是继续做了交易
and instead of pulling up, you went ahead and closed the deal.
我读过你让妓女为你口交的记录
I read this report where you got blowed by this whore,
而且你还真把这事记录在案了
and you actually wrote it that you got blowed
你看到的东西 你都信吗
You believe everything you read?
听着 伙计 我说的是
Look, man, all I'm saying,
如果要我从你这儿拿货 那公平点跟我分成啊
if I'm gonna take your package, split me and be fair.
我还得给我的人一样的钱 你却要抬我的价
I mean I got to pay all my people the same and you upping the price on me.
那你的人就给少点
Pay your people less.
可他们是我的人啊
They my people, though.
那就自己拿少点
Show it yourself.
六四开
Split it 60/40.
要更好的分成? 抄家伙呗
You want better? You need to tool up.
等着Chris Snoop  还有我的其他手下去"探望"你们吧
I'll wait for Chris, Snoop, and the rest  of my people call on your people.
你们那些鸟人 我们一下就搞掂
We will be brief with all you motherfuckers.
我想你懂的
I think you know.
好吧
All right.
在Fulton街往北
Northbound on Fulton.
Lester 往你那边去了
Lester, coming your way.
- 我看见他了 - 收到
- I see him.  - Roger that.
天天都是这些破事
Every day, same shit.
- 看看这个靓婊子 - 起立
- Look at this pretty bitch.  - Ten-hut!
他妈的坐下吧
Just sit the fuck down.
你们假装尊重上级 我不会因此假装不爽的
I'm not gonna pretend to be insulted because you all are pretending to respect the rank.
今天的特别调查指挥官
Today, he's an SIC.
明日也许就是新科警督
Tomorrow, he might be a newly minted lieutenant.
你永远也摸不透 这些关心前程的家伙会怎么样
You never know with these career-minded motherfuckers doing.
如果我在乎我的前程
If I was minding my career,
我会跑到西区来 只会你们这些没用的鸟人吗
would I be in the Western  in command of you useless fucking humps?
好了 咱先说说通知 再说说命令
OK, let's go to the readouts and the warrants first.
- 去他娘的通知 - 去他娘的命令
- Fuck the readouts.  - Fuck the warrants.
我们的工时怎么回事
What the fuck is going on with our hours?
对啊
Yeah.
别急 别急 我要是得到答复 肯定就告诉你们了
Easy, easy. If I had an answer, you'd have an answer.
我跟各位是一样的处境
I'm in the same boat as you.
我有五周没拿加班和出庭津贴了
It's five weeks since I've seen overtime or court pay,
我得还互助储金会的债 还得向教区付孩子的学费
and I gotta pay the credit union,  the archdiocese for my kid's tuition
还要给我前妻钱  好让她付钱给她那混蛋律师
and my ex-wife so she can pay her cunt of an attorney...
他妈的闭嘴坐下
Shut the fuck up and sit the fuck down!
坐到位子上去
In your fucking seats.
加班工时我们继续认
We're still authorizing overtime
出庭的工资单  州检官也还是签名认账的
and the state's attorneys  are still signing court slips.
但你们他妈的就是没给钱
But you ain't fucking paying us.
工会说要找全国劳资委处理这事
The union says we're going down to the NLRB and deal with this shit.
据说等市政预算情况改善了
Word coming down is that when the city's budget situation is improved,
咱就会补发或者当加班费发
we'll all see that as back pay or comp time.
- 一个钟头不少 - 补发个鬼
- Every last hour.  - Back pay my ass.
这破东西都是些破纸
This shit here is just paper.
65小时的加班记录 屁用没有
65 hours of worthless paper right here.
Brown警官 给我坐下
Officer Brown, sit your ass.
坐下
Sit!
我们都是职业警察
We're all professionals.
这是世界上治安情况最险峻的城市之一
And we're about to  police the roughest district
我们维持的又是它最险峻社区的治安
in one of the roughest cities in the world.
得有点精气神吧
Show some pride.
既然都答应了 肯定会兑现的
If promises were made, promises will be kept.
目前我市的情况是不好
The situation in the city right now is bad
但不会永远这糟
but it won't stay bad forever.
那我们就要像职业人士一样 等待转机
We wait this out like professionals.
好了 咱还是回头说说通知吧
Now, then, back to the readouts.
第一项是车辆调度场来的
First item is from motor pool.
在没有进一步通知前 不得送修任何有或没有标志的警车
No marked or unmarked units can be shopped on Dickman Street until further notice.
什么
What?
因预算减少 所以要求各分局
Cutbacks and fleet budgeting require that all districts
将就使用目前的车辆 也就是说...
make do with vehicles in their current state of repairs. That means...
这些烂车都要散架了 他们就他妈的不知道吗
Shitbox cars are falling apart, don't they fucking know that?
你在哪儿
Where you at?
在他后面
On his ass.
- 你们给盯牢了啊 - 没问题的 Lester 一切顺利
- You guys got the eyeball. - All good, Lester. It's all good.
他们都不乐意了吧
Natives are restless, huh?
不知道咱们还能撑多久
I don't know how long we go before the wheels fall off the cart.
一年前 他们还答应要提薪  增加退休金
A year ago, they were promised pay raises, pension bumps,
更好的装备 更好的车
better equipment, better cars.
现在可是连加班费都付不起
Now we can't even pay the OT.
跟他们讲了职业精神那一套了吧
Gave them the professionalism bit, right?
现实世界中 职业人士都是拿工资的 所以才叫职业人士
In the real world, they pay professionals. That's why we call them pros.
警司长 后面停车场出事了
Major, there's a problem on the back lot.
- 如果你觉得不爽 就清理呗 - 操蛋吧你
- If it really bothers you, clean them up. - Fuck you, son.
你才操蛋
Fuck you right back.
我午夜交接车的时候 那玩意儿就在那儿了 不信问人去
That thing was all fucked up when I got it for midnight, ask anyone.
你来清理 不然你找午夜班的那些人清理
You clean it or you get the midnight shift to clean it.
清理啊
Clean this.
去你的 Gene  总不能就这么留着给下一班的人吧
Fuck you, Gene. You don't leave it  like that for the next man.
像个娘们那样哭哭啼啼的是你 Bobby
You're the one whining like a little bitch, Bobby.
作为指挥官 我该去阻止他们吗
As SIC should I stop this?
怎么 你觉得这可以提升士气什么的吗
What, you think this is good for morale or something?
这些家伙几周没拿到钱了
These guys haven't had an honest paycheck in weeks.
根本咱就没有士气 警司
We have no fucking morale, Sergeant.
这屁孩带着我们兜了半小时了
Kid ran us around for half an hour.
妙吧
Amazing, ain't it?
来了
Here we go.
我们要接头
Got a meeting.
- 要我去吗 - 不不
- Want me to come?  - No, no.
你去看看你负责的那个买卖点 有事我让人带话给你
You go check on your corner. I'll send word if it's on.
- 他要走了 - 好的
- He's moving.  - All right.
Lester 在吗
Lester, are you there?
跟Chris在Reisterstown
Up on Reisterstown with Chris.
Marlo要走了
Marlo's on the move.
我们要跟踪他吗
Should we follow him?
干嘛啊 我们知道他要去哪儿
Why? We know where he's going.
不 先生 已经减到伤筋动骨了
No, sir, we've cut it to the bone already.
那些车下个月还要继续用
The cars are gonna go in service for the next month.
能捱多久算多久 而且加班费和出庭津贴也都拖着没发
And for as long as we can get away with it, we're deferring all overtime and court pay.
犯罪率呢 数据如何
How's crime? How are your stats?
这么缩减开支  你想要的两位数递减是没法实现的
The double-digit decline you wanted, not possible with these cuts.
看在上帝份上  你的犯罪率总得有所下降吧
For God's sake, you got to show us some kind of reduction.
- 我可是靠这个才竞选上来的 - 拖欠的加班费...
- I campaigned on that. - All this deferred overtime...
有办法了我们就马上付 至于我答应过的提薪
We'll pay it as we can. And the pay raises I promised?
还是会有的 就是迟一年实现罢了
They're still coming, just a year late.
现在我得把所有的钱花在学校上
Right now I got to throw  every dollar at the schools,
但你去跟你的人说 我知道我做过承诺
but you tell your people I know I made promises.
还能在什么地方节流呢
Where else can you guys trim?
呃 我们在进行一项冗长的调查
Well, we've been running a prolonged investigation...
就是去年我们在那些房子里发现的尸体
into all the bodies we pulled out of those houses last year.
好几个月的监视 几千个工时
Months of surveillance. Thousands of man-hours.
目前还没法逮人
At this point, we're not close to an arrest.
你是说要我们停止调查...
You're saying you want us to come down on a case
22宗杀人弃尸案吗
in which 22 people were murdered and left to rot in city houses?
因为这些凶案 我们上了全国新闻
We caught national news coverage on those murders.
去年的
Last year.
我不希望别人以为我们放弃调查了
I don't want anyone saying we're giving up on those murders.
我不希望看到那样的标题
I don't want to see that headline.
但就目前的财政状况 我们可以...
But given our fiscal situation, we could...
暂时中止调查
temporarily suspend the investigation...
等待新的进展
pending new developments.
还有别的吗
Anything else?
咱得取消兼职十小时为上限的规定了
We need to take away the ten-hour cap on secondary employment.
你要是这么干 你的警察就撂摊子了
You do that and your police aren't doing police work.
他们会保护酒店 给夜店看场子  干建筑活儿去了
They're guarding liquor stores, bouncing nightclubs, putting up drywall.
说实在的 士气现在超低落
Respectfully, morale is at rock bottom.
你必须给我的人一点甜头...
You need to throw our people a bone...
不然就会永远失去他们
or you could lose them for good.
坚持住
Hold the line now
我们会有转机的 我保证
and we'll get to a better place, I promise.
说吧 Norman
Say it, Norman,
你不正想着吗
you're thinking it.
谏言不讳啊 Norman
Truth to power, Norman.
我留着你 不就是为了这个吗
Isn't that what I keep you around for?
州长给出五千多万的时候
When the governor threw that 50-some million on the table,
你就该收下
you should've picked that shit up.
他要是收了国家救助金 他就成不了州长了
He takes the state bail-out and he never becomes governor.
他裁减警局预算 犯罪率就居高不下
He shorts the police department, the crime rate stays up,
他还是成不了州长
he ain't no governor, neither.
只是一个破城市的烂市长
Just a weak-ass mayor of a broke-ass city.
- 感觉好些了? - 好一点
- Feel better? - A little bit.
你呢
You?
那小子想开了
Boy folded it up.
他要跟我们六四分账
He taking our shit 60/40.
嗯 那黑鬼就是没心没肺的
Yeah, nigger showed no heart at all.
- 我的人在那边可以放松戒备了吧? - 绝对的
- So my people could stand down there? - Definitely.
- 好吧 - 这摊子事就不想再搞什么动作了
- All right. - Won't need no drama behind this nonsense.
条子还是跟着你 对吧
And po-po's still up on you, huh?
嗯 一直没消停过
Yeah, hot all the time, man.
今天他们派了一个黑头发的白人小子
Today they got the white boy with the black hair
去了Booker T Washington学校的屋顶上
up on the roof with Booker T Washington.
用小望远镜监视
Watching with his spyglass.
手下人见到他上去了
The young 'un saw him climbing up. Yeah.
好吧 那咱就这么行事吧
All right, so we'll do like this, then.
就这么着了
That's it.
这么折腾就为了说这几句话
All of that so he could swap a few words.
这怎么窃听呢
How do you wiretap that?
- Lester?  - 今天是不是就到这儿了?
- Lester?  - Are we done for the day, man?
你不想跟着Chris  看他接下来去哪儿吗
You don't want to stay on Chris, see where he goes next?
我们跟了这家伙几个月了  他口风紧得很
We've been on this guy for months, man, he doesn't slip.
咱的加班费又没人付
And no one's kicking our OT.
行啊 就到这儿吧
Yeah. We're done.
收到
Copy that.
"温室气体"有卖 来爽下吧
Greenhouse gas right here. Gas up.
嗨 Marcus 还有货吗
Hey, Marcus, you got a count for me?
- Spider 还有货吗 - 你吗 没有
- Spider, you got a count for me? - For you? No.
情况如何
How we do?
说不准
Can't say for sure.
他们缺货了吗
They short, huh?
我只知道他们不肯说
Man, I just know they ain't told me.
"温室气体"有卖 来爽下吧
Greenhouse gas. Gas up on the green.
回家吧 伙计 Bug很快就放学了
Go home, man. Bug'll be out of school pretty soon.
我不是你 Michael
I ain't you, Michael.
去接Bug吧 今晚见
Go get Bug. I'll see you tonight.
"温室气体"有卖
Greenhouse gas right here.
唷 没问题吧
Yo, we short?
没啊 挺好 1400就卖剩60了 挺好的 Mike
No, we good. Got 60 left from 1,400. We on it, Mike.
那你怎么不告诉Duke?
So why you ain't tell Duke?
- 你怎么跟Duke过不去 黑鬼? - 我没跟谁过不去啊
- Why you fucking with Duke, nigger? - I ain't fucking with nobody, man.
是他神经过敏罢了 就这样
He just acting like a bitch, that's all.
"温室气体"很爽哦
Greenhouse gas is hot.
他们可是有点昏了头了
They're getting a little sloppier.
过去一周在同一个地点接头两次
Did that meet in the same lot they've used twice in the last week.
McCulloh的那个地方?
The one in McCulloh?
想想我们跟了他们多久 这还真是"挺好"的 Lester
That's pretty thin considering how long we've been on these guys, Lester.
他们懒了 都固定模式了
They're gonna get lazy, fall into a pattern.
随着时间流逝 他们慢慢都这样
They all do, over time.
谁说了加班?
Someone say overtime?
说真的 今天干了14个钟头 却只领8个钟头的薪水
We did 14 hours today and we'll only get paid for 8.
先苦后甜嘛
Cases gotta go green before they go black.
这是我的经验
That's how I was taught.
180小时了 还不断增加
180 hours and counting.
再多几周 就满一个月了
Couple more weeks and you get a month's work.
再多几周 我就坐牢去了 拖延支付小孩的赡养费
Couple more weeks, I'm gonna be in jail for late payment of child support.
谁要喝一杯
Who needs a taste?
屁 谁请客啊
Shit. Who's buying, motherfucker?
我请一两轮吧
I'll cover a round or two.
那我就喝它一两轮吧
Then I guess I'm drinking a round or two.
哇 还有船坞啊
Oh, yeah, and a boat dock, huh?
嗯 这个凉亭 是给我太太的
Yeah. And the gazebo here... for my wife.
警督 您有城里来的消息吗 说啥时候要还我们加班的钱?
??? You get any word from downtown on when they'll start paying out the OT again?
这些监视行动我们都是两班倒的
Cos we going double shift on these surveillances.
他们啥都没说
They haven't told me anything.
大概我不是圈内人吧
Guess I ain't in the loop.
得叫停了 警监
We have to shut it down, Colonel.
解释一下怎么会出现22具尸体的 解释给我听听
Explain to me how we come up on 22 bodies. Explain that to me.
这是市政厅下的令
This comes straight from the hall.
你说的可是我最强的手下一年的辛苦啊
You're talking about a year's worth of work by my best people.
就这么放弃了?
To just give up on all of that?
警监 咱们一个月发不出工资了
Colonel, we haven't made an honest payroll in over a month.
Carcetti在哪儿呢
Where the fuck is Carcetti?
这家伙曾许诺会有新的面貌
The man promised us a new day.
他重心放在学校 咱们就要等等了
He's tangled up with the schools and we're on hold.
市长私下跟我做了些承诺
The mayor's made a few commitments to me personally.
如果你想代表警局跟他算算账
If you want to call in a marker on behalf of this department,
我没意见
feel free.
同时再看看你能否  要回咱开公车回家的权利
And while you're at it, see if you can get your take-home car back.
预算员一小时前打来电话
Budget officer called an hour ago
说不再让警监及以下人员将公车开回家
telling us to relieve colonels and below of take-home vehicles.
等等 看 如果你这么放 我就赢了
Hold on. See, if you move it here, then I got you.
好吧 小家伙开战了啊
OK. The little man bringing it.
唷 Duke...
Yo, Duke...
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
如果你不愿意  就不用再到那个买卖点干了
You ain't need to put in time on the corner if you don't want.
你在这儿陪着Bug就够了 能领到钱了
I mean, you doing enough here with Bug to get paid.
什么意思
How you mean?
我是说 这么照顾他
I'm saying, looking out for him.
我一直在想  如果你因什么事被关起来
And I've been thinking, like, if you were to get locked up
那Bug会怎么样呢 你知道
for some shit, how'd it be for Bug, you know?
那早上谁来帮你看着那场子
So, who's gonna watch your corner in the morning?
我觉得可以提拔Spider
Thought I might promote Spider,
一两周内看看他干得怎么样
see how he do for a week or so.
那我不就成个保姆什么的了吗
So, I'd be like a nanny and shit?
Bug放学回家前 我得干什么
What am I gonna do before Bug get home from school,
擦炉子 再烤些曲奇吗
clean the stove and bake some cookies?
想干什么都行
Do what you wanna, yo.
他到家之前 时间你自己支配
Before he get home, time is your own.
你赢了我了
You beat me.
厉害啊 赢了我了
Oh, snap, you beat me.
操蛋的大话精 骗人的混蛋
Fucking liars, motherfucking liars.
别气啊 伙计
Easy, boy.
我当巡警时可开心呢 挺好的啊
I was happy on patrol. I was fine.
- 你觉得没劲啊 - 不是 我开心着呢
- You were bored. - Fuck no. I was happy.
那些混蛋找到我 说
Motherfuckers come to me and say,
"全新的局面啊 Jimmy"
"It's a new day, Jimmy,"
说了一堆会怎么变革的屁话
talking shit about how it was gonna change.
他妈的根本没变化
Shit never fucking changes.
如果他们当时让我查下去
If they had left me up and running
Marlo窃听他们的手机的时候
when Marlo was on them cell phones,
我一年前就逮住他了
I'd have had him a year ago.
瞧见了? 可他们就是不干正事
See? But they can't do the right thing.
那压根不是他们的风格
It ain't in them.
现在我们又重查Marlo了 那就得24小时盯着他
Now we're back on Marlo's ass, we need to be on him 24/7.
那些混蛋断了咱的加班钱
The motherfuckers cut our overtime
还把最好的监视车辆送修了
and they shopped our best surveillance van.
就更别指望能申请...
Don't even think about trying to requisition
一架新的数码相机了
a new fucking digital camera.
他们想用最省钱的方式查案
They want to do it on the cheap.
- Bunk巡游来了 - 嗨 Bunky Bunk 过来
- Bunk on the prowl. - Hey, Bunky-Bunk, come here.
- Jimmy - 过来 你这猛男
- Jimmy. - Come here, you virile beast.
来啊 Bunk 给我买杯酒 婊子
Come on, Bunk. Buy me a drink, you whore.
用啥买啊
With what?
我还以为上头至少会想法子
I'd have thought the bosses would've at least figured out
给凶杀组发工资呢
how to keep paying Homicide.
Pete 得了吧 帮我解决这些单子
Pete, come on. Take these slips off me.
这里一块钱顶我半块钱的帐
I'll pay you 50 cents on the dollar against my tab.
只收现金
Cash only.
等我们发钱了 你不就有双倍收入嘛
When we get paid, you double your money.
市政从来不会真的足额补发工资的
City's never gonna be healthy enough to go all that back pay.
那酒吧的账单咱们怎么付
How the fuck are we gonna pay the bar tab?
可以抢劫卖酒的商店呗
We could always knock off a liquor store.
Edmondson大街上的G & L  玻璃很薄 我可以搞掂酒保
G & L on Edmondson. Thin Plexi, I'd take out the counter man.
- 我掩护你 - 门我来解决 没问题
- I'll cover you. - I got the door, no problem.
谁来开车呢
Who's gonna be our wheel man?
每个计划都有一个薄弱环节
Every plan, a weak link.
听说要关了国外的机构
I heard they're closing the foreign bureaus -
南非的 中国的 全都关
Jo'burg, Beijing, everything.
- 听说费城的下岗情况也一样严重 - 胡说 他们不会下岗的
- I heard layoffs as bad as in Philly. - Bullshit, they're not gonna lay off.
他们会先发一次性遣散费
They'll offer buyouts first.
如果钱不够了 再让人下岗
If they don't get enough, they'll go right to layoffs.
你管这些干嘛 你的资历那么深
What the fuck you care? You got all the seniority in the world.
编辑部解雇干了20几年的 太糟糕了
Be a shame to rid of them twentysomethings in the newsroom.
堕落的混蛋
Degenerate motherfucker.
嗯 Kleppner肯定喜欢雇些年轻的
Yeah. Kleppner sure do like to hire them sweet, young things.
二十三四岁 模特身材
23, 24 years old, model-thin.
直长发 亮闪闪的大眼睛
Long, straight hair and big traffic-light eyes.
而一半人是啥都不会写 对吧
And half of them can't write a lick, can they?
对啊 咱这受人尊敬的总编
Yeah, our esteemed managing editor.
肯定有某种偏好 对吧
Certainly does favor a certain type, don't he?
男人嘛
Gentlemen...
那可难说
Question mark.
有一天 我要感受一下...
Someday, I want to find out what it feels like
为一家真正的报纸工作是啥滋味
to work for a real newspaper.
怎么 我出去采访了
What? I've got calls out.
现在就开始写
You start writing now,
我总不能今晚十点 还在这儿重新弄你的导语吧
and I'm not here ten o'clock tonight reworking your lead.
- 重新弄我的导语? - 拜托 Fletch
- Reworking my lead? - Come on, Fletch.
这辈子至少一次 赶上报纸二编的期限吧
Try to make the e-dot deadline for once in your life.
- 市政会议的事吧 - 嗯
- A-matter for the council meeting? - Yeah.
只要有新消息  我就让它上头条 再付印
I'll top it with whatever smells fresh, make the double-dot.
他们要投票决定一个 针对无家可归者的法令 对吧
They're gonna vote on a homeless ordinance, right?
也许不是 Nerese放出风声
Maybe not. Nerese is making noises
说要把这事交回给市政委员会处理
like she might throw it back to committee.
是吗 反正找地方给我弄新闻来
Yeah? Well, find me some news somewhere.
有地方着火了
Something's burning.
你们...想知道是怎么回事吗
You... wondered what it might be?
嗨 我又不是警讯记者
Hey, I'm not the police reporter.
但你可以打给Twigg 对吧
But you called Twigg, though, right?
至少他是个专栏作家 给他钱就得好好坐着写
At least he's a columnist, he's paid to sit on his ass.
你的借口又是什么
What's your excuse?
让他呆在抽烟区 打自己手机去
Just left him in the smoking lounge. Hit him on his cell.
什么人会无所事事地看火灾呢
What kind of people stand around watching a fire?
真是可悲啊
Some shameful shit right here.
你们还想上哪儿去呢  孩子们
Where else would you rather be, huh, kids?
嗨 Gus
Hey, Gus.
嗨 Jay
Hey, Jay.
美联社有城市减少公交线路的报道
A.P. Has got something on more cutbacks in city bus lines.
不是吧
You don't say.
Daily Record报今天早上就报道了 汽车贸易协会的试探性行为
Daily Record had it this morning. M.T.A. Trial balloon.
本州新闻部也报道了
State desk is covering.
Daily Record
Daily Record.
好了 各位 现在是两点钟 我要大家的新闻概要
All right, people, it's two o'clock, I need budget lines
防止有人又想威胁拖搞
in case anybody's threatening to commit an act of daily journalism.
本市新闻部 我是Haynes
City desk. Haynes.
你没有啊
You didn't, huh?
那中心版面的图片怎么办
What the fuck are we supposed to do for centerpiece art?
好 好极了
Great. Wonderful.
赛马报道的照片出不来了
Photo didn't get out for the racetrack piece.
Hopkins新闻发布会的照片呢
What about art for the Hopkins press conference?
之前把它换成赛马报道了 嗨 Swag 还是我
Scratched it for racetrack. Hey, Swag, it's me again.
巴尔的摩东部有地方着火了
Something's on fire over in East Baltimore.
弄个漂亮照片来给我惊喜下吧
Surprise me with a nice, pretty picture, huh?
听着 我们查到的是毒品暴力犯罪 而且是很多
Look, what we have is drug violence and plenty of it.
你们说的是联邦枪支法
What you have are federal gun statutes that
五年的最低刑期 不得保释
come with a five-year minimum, no parole,
我们需要降低命案率
and we need to lower our murder rate.
在你削减了警察局的预算的时候吗
Especially since you shorted your police department budget.
我们财政经费紧 不是什么秘密
It's no secret we have budget problems,
所以司法部要介入
all the more reason for the US Attorney to pitch in.
正经地说 我最需处理的是反暴行
Officially, my priorities are counterterrorism
还有政治腐败
and political corruption.
我当时请求你协查
So you told me when I asked you for help
空屋弃尸的时候你也是这么说的
on those bodies in the vacant houses.
但我现在愿意向你们提供十几位联邦探员
But I'm inclined to provide you with a dozen FBI agents
还有他们所需的所有办案资金
and all the wherewithal they need to work that case.
但我们希望Clay Davis接受联邦审讯
But we want Clay Davis to go federal.
我们的州检已经立案了
Our state's attorney has developed that case.
所以要由州检来做决定
Our state's attorney decides what to do with it.
他此刻似乎想让Davis先生在本地受审
He seems inclined to keep Mr. Davis local at this point.
但如果你可以让Bond先生重新考虑
But if you could convince Mr. Bond to reconsider,
我们也许可以找到些资源
we might find the resources
不单是调查那些弃尸
not only for the probe of the row-house bodies,
还可以帮你们查那些枪支案
but the time to run some of those gun cases for you.
但如果你得不到Clay Davis 你就会任由杀戮继续下去
But unless you get Clay Davis, you'll let the killing continue.
听着 FBI和联邦检察署
Now look, the FBI and the US Attorney's office
不是来这儿做你们警察局做不了的事的
are not here to do the job that your police department can't.
你们无能 别怪在我们头上
Don't blame us for your ineffectiveness.
巴尔的摩已经是腥风血雨了
Baltimore is knee deep in blood.
除非这家伙能把一个民主党议员送上绞架
Unless this guy can hang a Democratic legislator,
否则他才没所谓
he couldn't give a damn.
为了保护这名议员
And to protect that legislator,
碰巧是本州一位腐败的勒索高手
who happens to be one of the most corrupt extortion artists in the state,
你会自绝后路 是吧
you'll burn every last bridge.
你以为我在乎Clay Davis吗
Do you think I give a shit about Clay Davis?
- 我不是在保护他 - 那就把他交出来
- I am not protecting him. - Then give him up.
- 那是Bond说了算的 跟他谈去 - 我谈过了
- It's Bond's call. Talk to him. - I have.
他告诉你们共和党人滚一边去 对吧
And he told your Republican ass to go fuck itself?
那我就再说一次吧
Well, let me double down on that.
祝处理犯罪问题好运
Good luck with your crime problem.
很顺利嘛
That go well?
你知道他为什么这么急着 要自己调查Clay Davis吗
You know why he wants the Clay Davis investigation so bad?
那样他就可以对民主党踩上一脚
So he can stomp all over the Democratic party
然后帮他的共和党高尔夫球友
and help give his asshole Republican golf buddy
再连任四年州长
another four years in the governor's mansion.
Bond不想把案子交出来 也是为了帮助政党 对吧
So, Bond is keeping the case local to help the party, huh?
不 Bond留着这案子
No. Bond is keeping the case so that
是为了让Clay Davis成为他的战利品
Clay Davis can be a trophy for Bond.
我猜咱们新当选的州检官
My guess is, our newly elected state's attorney
想要有一天竞选市长
wants to, one day, run for mayor.
你就两头为难了 Nerese
Cuts both ways for you, Nerese.
如果联邦检察署得到Clay Davis
If the Feds get Clay Davis,
那这个案子就没法让Bond树形象
then the case doesn't give Bond any profile,
但如果他们得到了 又让他反水
But if they get him and flip him,
Clay就把Royce一半的管理团队拉下水
Clay might take half the Royce administration with him.
也许也包括你
You included, maybe.
你不用担心我
Don't you worry about me.
而你恰恰在我们需要帮助的时候
You, on the other hand, just slammed the door on the feds,
拒绝了联邦检察署的人
when we need all the help we can get.
那是他们的错
That's on them.
难过美人关啊
Pussy call.
我很高兴知道Marlo有这嗜好
I'm just glad to know Marlo has a hobby.
带她到房间去
Take her to her room,
让她喝喝酒 看看电视
You know, let her hit the minibar, watch TV.
等她安顿好了 我们就处理其他事情
When she's settled, we'll take care of the other thing.
我让Monk来给我开车
I'll use Monk for my ride.
好吧 那谈谈新的议题
All right, then, moving on to new business,
霍普金斯大学买下了Monument大街以北
with John Hopkins buying up everything
所有地盘 在拆除旧屋
north of Monument Street and tearing the shit down,
我想我们都知道东巴尔的摩墙上的广告语了
I think we all see the writing on the wall in East Baltimore.
对 他们把混混都赶走了
Yeah. They moving the hood out.
黑鬼要越线进入巴尔的摩郡了
Yo, niggers are going across the line to Baltimore County.
很快 东巴尔的摩就不再是Essex的地盘了
Pretty soon, East Baltimore won't be in Essex.
沿40号公路一直到Turner车站 那儿已经有市场了
There's a market already along route 40 and down at Turner Station.
新的地盘是谁说了归谁
And new territory go to who claim it.
不 一般是这样
No. Ordinarily so.
但我们有些...
But here we got some of
东区的人正被赶出来 对吧
our east-side people being displaced, right?
我觉得我们该关照受影响最大的
I think we need to take care of those most affected.
也就是你
Meaning you.
很大程度上 我在东区干
Well, I am east side, for the most part.
可我说的是Hungry Man 还有Parker和Ghost
But I'm talking about Hungry Man and Parker and Ghost.
除了我 还有其他人
You know, others beside myself.
霍普金斯不会影响你的市场份额的 Marlo
Hopkins ain't gonna affect your market share, Marlo.
- 对我们中那些受影响的... - 好吧 我明白了
- So for those of us who suffer... - All right, I see that.
干吗不找你的马仔去干一票
Why don't you let one of your juniors get a shot
去打开局面
to open the county up?
让一个生面孔去干
Let a fresh face get a shot at it.
无意冒犯 孩子 但我怎么给我的手下派活儿
No disrespect, son, but how I delegate to my lieutenants
不是合作的重点
is not a co-op concern.
嗯 但Slim对此有何感觉呢
Yeah, but how Slim feel about that, though?
你感觉如何 高佬? 准备好为我们当先锋吗
How you feel, tall man? Ready to pioneer out there for us?
不 我现在这样挺好
Nah, I'm good where I am.
Marlo 伙计 你有些过了
Marlo, man, you're a little out of order here.
嗯 呃 就是一个想法
Yeah, well, it's just a thought.
听着 这个分成...
Look, man, what's the percentage breakdown...
对Marlo不可大意
Don't sleep on Marlo.
他有古怪
He up to some shit here.
那可是一流的小区
That was some prime real estate.
我花了六年才把它们变成买卖场
It took me six years to build up them corners.
Reginald
Reginald.
我要去上班了 你知道我这周都是夜班
I'm going to work, you know I got night shift all this week.
我会在这儿安静呆着
You know, I could stay down here quiet like,
你不用紧张
you ain't need to sweat.
我不在的时候 你不能在这儿 咱们说好了的
You don't stay here when I'm not around. That's our rule.
我是你哥哥 我要是离开了 就没地方可去了
I'm your brother. I got nowhere to go when I leave.
上次我留你一个人在我家
Last time I left you alone in my home,
你把我厨房里的半数东西都拿去当了
you dragged half my kitchen to a pawn shop.
记得吗
Remember that?
但你可以把门锁了 对吧
But you can keep the door locked, right?
我就在这下面
I'm down here.
我说了算
My rules.
你说过的
You said.
法院? 他妈的怎么回事
The courthouse? What the fuck?
我去
I'll go in.
Rupert
Rupert.
怎么了
What now?
重案组被裁减了
Major crimes is being disbanded.
探员都回去干日常工作
The detectives return to regular rotation.
我昨天接到上头的命令 市长签字同意了
I got the word yesterday from command. The mayor signed off.
他们要悄悄地放弃
They're quietly deep-sixing the investigation
对弃尸和Marlo Stanfield的案子
into the bodies and Marlo Stanfield.
- 缺钱吗 - 什么都要紧缩
- A money thing? - They're pulling back on everything.
人工 装备 化验 还有用车
Man hours, equipment, lab work, motor pool.
能找到的每个子儿
Every last dollar we can find is being
都用去填补学校系统的预算了
shipped over to plug the school system budget.
Cedric觉得他可以试着说服Carcetti
Cedric thought he would try to reason with Carcetti,
看看是否至少能保住Stanfield的小组
maybe see if we can keep the Stanfield detail, at least.
Clay Davis呢? 这案子很快要交给大陪审团了
What about Clay Davis? That's going to grand jury soon.
等等 如果他们把Freamon调回凶杀组
If they ship Freamon back to homicide,
他这事我也没辙了
I don't have him on that, either,
而Lester就是那案子
and Lester pretty much is that case.
打扰 你们知道书记员办公室在哪儿吧
Excuse me. Y'all know where the clerk's office at?
- 刑事还是民事 - 肯定是刑事啊
- Criminal or civil? - Criminal, definitely.
大厅尽头 最后一扇门
End of the hall, last door.
- 你们什么时候见市长 - 大概一小时后
- When are you meeting the mayor? - About an hour.
他们在他下班前给我们几分钟时间
They gave me a few minutes on the end of his day.
我跟你们去  去的时候到办公室叫我一声
I'll go with you. Come by my office and get me.
那你现在要去哪儿
So, where you off to now?
18室的动议聆讯会 日程表上的最后一项
Motions hearing in part 18. It's the last thing on my sched.
本州新闻部呢
And for state desk?
城市公交路线传说要裁减
Additional cutbacks are said to be coming in the city M.T.A. Routes.
- 州长的试探性行为 - 影响了很多人呢 对吧
- Trial balloon from the governor. - Affects a lot of people, no?
要真实施才是啊 之前就流产过一次
If it happens. They floated this once before.
我们还是可以出去采访 让他们知道潜在的影响
Still, we can go outside and give them the potential impact.
事实上 我们报道这个 是跟了Daily Record的风
Well, the truth is, we're following the Daily Record on this one.
我们怎么没收到风声呢 如果这是放风试探...
Why don't we have that? If it's a trial balloon...
上次遣散之后
We've been without a transport reporter
咱就没有跑交通的记者了 所以...
since the last round of buyouts, so...
- 咱还是得收到风的啊 - 也许吧 但是...
- We should still pick that up. - Probably so, but...
芝加哥那边勒紧了裤腰带
Just because Chicago tightens its belt,
不等于我们也得跟着倒霉啊
it's no reason for us to fall down.
他们那边的紧缩不该影响我们...
Their cutbacks there shouldn't affect our ability
办出色报纸的能力
to put out an excellent product.
只不过要用更小的成本做更好的报纸罢了
Simply have to do more with less.
我们的资源比Daily Record多
We have more resources than the Daily Record.
虽然没有交通记者
Though not a transport reporter.
阁下是去采访今天的地铁会议了?
Your eminence, slumming at the Metro meeting today?
- 你知道啥啊 - 本市新闻部
- What do you know? - City desk.
州检官抱怨说
State's attorney complains about
警察福利质量下降
the decline in quality police casework,
Warmcastle负责20英寸版面的报道 今晚收到市议会消息
20 inches from Warmcastle. Got the city council tonight.
不会对无家可归者提案进行表决
Won't get a vote on the homeless initiative,
但我们会弄到相关新闻的
but we'll scratch some news out somehow.
Beltway有两起车祸死亡 市里昨晚发生两起命案
Two-car fatal on the Beltway, two overnight murders in the city,
巴尔的摩联排住宅区正发生火灾
and a fire ongoing in a Baltimore City row house
这新闻我们拍不拍到照片还说不准
for which we may or may not have art.
地区事件部
Regional affairs.
我们有霍普金斯大学有关种族研究的报道
We have the Hopkins piece on biomed,
虽然他们说没有拍到新闻发布会的照片
though I'm told we didn't get art on today's press conference.
大学特约通讯员 提供15英寸版面报道
And 15 inches from the college park stringer
有关马里兰大学废除种族隔离的 目标还没有实现
on UM not making it's deseg goals again.
我听说 撇开数据
I'm told that, numbers aside,
校园里对少数人种敌意更浓了
the campus has become much more hospitable to minorities.
我听说情况是好转了
I'm told things have changed for the better.
真的吗
Really?
你们都知道Gene Robbins 那里的新闻系主任
As you may know, Gene Robbins is dean of journalism there.
前几天我跟他一起吃午饭
I had lunch with him the other day...
- 但是他们还没有... - 他说
- Nevertheless, they haven't... - and he was saying
过去几年学校在对黑人员工和学生方面
how the last few years have really transformed the school's reputation
名声大有改观
with black faculty and students.
- 他是白人 对吧 - 谁
- He's a white guy, right? - Who?
新闻系那家伙啊 Wormer主任 Martin主任 管他叫什么
Journalism fellow. Dean Wormer, Dean Martin - whatever his name is.
我在费城曾跟Gene Robbins共事
I worked with Gene Robbins in Philadelphia.
他是个优秀的记者 说话也是靠谱的
He is an excellent journalist and a reliable source.
我觉得讲种族的离题了
I think race is beside the point.
咱们何不坚持废除种族隔离不成功的报道
So why don't we hold on the deseg story
直到咱能派出更多人去采访为止呢
until we can assign someone to do some more reporting,
真正弄清少数人种如何看待马里兰大学
get a real sense of how UM is perceived by minorities?
好吧 再充实内容
All right, then. Let's firm things up,
一小时后再看看情况
Take a look at where we stand an hour from now.
干嘛去惹他 你知道Gene Robbins是谁
Why poke him with a stick? You know who Gene Robbins is.
谁惹他了
Who's poking?
如果我有报道的想法 我就会说出来
If I think something about a story, I'm gonna speak on it.
你知道健康的编辑部是什么样的吗
You know what a healthy newsroom is?
那是个神奇的地方  人们总在争论一切
It's a magical place where people argue about everything all the time.
- 我没有招谁惹谁 - "Martin主任"?
- I'm not poking anyone here. - "Dean Martin"?
好吧 惹了一点
Yeah, a little poke.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道今天不用出庭
I know that wasn't no court date.
枪支案的庭审已经推迟两次了
You already got the gun charge postponed twice.
到底怎么回事
So what the fuck was that about?
记得咱因为谋杀被关押的俄罗斯人吗
Remember that Russian we locked up for murder,
几年前港口案子的其中一名
part of the port case years back?
那案子我没跟你一起办
I didn't work that case with you, man.
所以 不记得了
So, no, I don't remember.
Chris Partlow记得
Well, Chris Partlow does.
Gutierrez小姐
Miss Gutierrez.
Gutierrez
Gutierrez!
过来
Get your ass over here.
嗯
Yeah.
你说清空了120人
You say that 120 people were evacuated.
是的
Yeah. They were.
人不能说"清空"
You can't evacuate people.
你想这么说也行
I mean, you can, if you want,
但你在这里不是这个意思
but that's not what you want to say here.
可以清空一幢大楼
A building can be evacuated.
清空一个人就是给他灌肠
To evacuate a person is to give that person an enema.
注意细节 Gutierrez小姐
The details, Miss Gutierrez.
在巴尔的摩太阳报 我们还是对细节奉若神明的
At the Baltimore Sun, God still resides in the details.
你给他们上了一课 Spry
You teach them, Spry.
现在该把这些小孩怎么办啊
What are we gonna do  with these children today?
他妈的该死
Fuckety-fuck.
又一个烧焦的娃娃
Another burnt doll.
又是Carlyle
Carlyle again.
- 摄影部 - 我要找巴尔的摩东区火灾的照片
-Photo.  -I'm looking at the fire art from East Baltimore
然后我拿到一张前景是烧焦的芭比的照片
and I got a burnt Barbie in foreground.
- 怎么 - 怎么
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
如果拍照的不是Carlyle 我也许还相信你
And I might actually believe you if it wasn't Carlyle who took the shot.
我根本不信这照片是拍来的 给我拍点别的
No fuckin' way I believe in this picture. Print me something else.
他拍来的每张火灾照片
Every fire photo he brings in
肯定在废墟里就有个烧焦的娃娃
there's got to be some burnt doll somewhere in the debris.
我知道那不老实的混蛋 带着一堆该死的娃娃
I can see that cheating motherfucker now with his fucking harem of dolls
然后在那儿就点着一个
pouring lighter fluid on each one.
你去查查他车上  肯定能找到一整套娃娃
You check his fucking trunk, you'll find a whole collection.
你有什么消息
What's your lead?
在Carcetti的要求下 议会推迟对无家可归者提案进行表决
Council delays vote on the homeless initiative at Carcetti's behest.
他不希望市政府看起来 像要把无家可归者赶出市中心
He doesn't want it to look like the city's running the homeless out of downtown,
所以他要求Nerese重新拟定措施
so he asked Nerese to redraft the measure.
他说得对 是不能把人清空
He's right. You don't evacuate people.
- 什么 - 没什么
- What? - Never mind.
- 弄到什么好新闻吗 - 日间警察没留意的事情
- Working on anything good? - Just what day cops missed.
Charles郡有一起死亡事件 市中心有一起煤气泄漏
A fatal in Charles County and a gas leak downtown.
简讯吧
Briefs, huh?
目前为止 安静的一天
Quiet day so far.
- 这是个负面新闻之城 - 你觉得是吗
- It's a shit news town. - You think?
这里有多少新闻上了全国新闻? 没多少
How many stories go national out of here? Not many.
去年那些房子里的弃尸  就大赚眼球
Those bodies in the houses last year. That got a lot of play.
他们案子都没破 对吧
And they didn't even solve it, right?
这报道根本就没后续
The story had no legs at all.
从那之后 还有啥?
Since then, what else?
Jeff  Jeffy-Jeff
Jeff. Jeffy-Jeff.
干嘛
What?
过来 老天
Come here. Jesus Christ.
又怎么了
What now?
你听完规划提案会了吗
Did you stay for the zoning bills?
- 没 我赶回来写报道了 - 去资料库查查
- No, I came back here to write. - Check the fucking library.
该死 也查查剪报  这事大有渊源
Shit, check the clips too. It goes back a-ways.
不不不 看看 你回市政厅去 拿到关于此事的投票结果
No no no. Check that. You go back to  the hall, you get the vote on this thing.
看看是谁发起的
Find out who sponsored this.
查出是Carcetti还是Nerese  或是其他背后主使
Find out whether Carcetti or Nerese or whoever's behind it.
强迫他们开口 查查这里头什么鬼
You buttonhole them, find out what the hell's going on.
为什么 谁是Ricardo Hendrix?
Why? Who's Ricardo Hendrix?
毒贩 外号大脸Rick
A drug dealer. Fatface Rick.
Alma  Scott 巴尔的摩街的这出房产 是一家脱衣舞俱乐部
Alma, Scott, this property on Baltimore Street is a titty bar
市政需要Howard街的企业区
the city wants for the Howard Street enterprise zone,
但他们要跟他交换的地产...
but this other property they want to trade with him,
我想查出是怎么回事
I want to find out what that's all about.
他们要跟毒贩交换地产?
This is a drug dealer they're trading properties with?
对 他的前科多得很  还有几起是定罪了的
He's got a record as long as your arm. Couple of convictions too.
快去 弄些好的访谈回来
Go, go. Get some good quotes.
Alma 我要你到这个地址去
Alma... I want you to go to this address.
是一家叫Desperado的脱衣舞俱乐部
It's a strip club called Desperado.
你周围问问 找经营者 他的名字叫Ricardo Hendrix
You ask around for the owner. His name's Ricardo Hendrix.
你告诉他们 在没得到回应之前 我们要天天把Ricky放头版
You tell them until we get a comment, we'll put Ricky on the front page every day.
他是谁
Who is he?
是个毒贩
He's a drug dealer.
但这事从表面看 他是在市政厅搞什么鬼了
But from the look of this, he's running some sort of game at city hall.
我们要他说说为何要跟市政府交换房产
We want a comment as to why he's trading property with the city,
- 他想从中获什么利 - 好
- what he stands to make off the deal. - OK.
你要我干什么
What do you want from me?
查资料 看看停尸间的卷宗
Pull clips, check the morgue files,
查Ricardo过往的底细
write the A-matter on Ricardo's history.
等等 她去脱衣舞俱乐部 而我却要到停尸间去查资料?
Wait, she goes to strip clubs and I'm pulling clips in the morgue?
- 议会的会议你要迟到了吧 - 要来找你
- You late for the council meeting? - Looking for you.
我? 我一直在跑呢 Walters的慈善活动要迟到了
Me? I'm racing. Late for some charity thing at the Walters'.
市长先生 我听说今晚可以给我几分钟
Mr. Mayor, I was told I could get a few minutes tonight.
- 今天有预约时间给你吗 - 今天什么事都迟到
- You're on my schedule? - Everything ran late today.
- 他们应该打电话给你的 我想 - 怎么 是快点说完 还是另约时间
- They were supposed to ring you, I think. - What, do it quick or do we resched?
Burrell要解散办空屋弃尸案的小组
Burrell's disbanded the unit that's working the bodies in the houses.
等我们宽裕了 你们就可以回来办案
When we're fat with money, you can come back on it.
调查不是这么回事的
Investigations are not like that.
不能中断一个案子  然后就能随便重启 而不用...
You can't just drop one and then pick it up down the road without...
警监 我们没钱 屁钱都没有
Colonel, we got no money. No fucking money at all.
在新的财政拨款到位前 我们一点办法没有
There's nothing we can do until the new fiscal.
但是 Tommy 那我的Clay Davis案也没辙了 我们就要提交大陪审团了
But, Tommy, that kills Clay Davis for me and we're about to go to grand jury on it.
调查的Clay的是同一个小组?
Same unit is doing Clay?
我这边也需要一点猛料的
I need some profile for my shop.
搞掂这个案子你需要小组的几个人
How much of that unit do you need to bring the case in?
几名探员就好
A couple of detectives.
我会告诉Rawls 你可以留下两名探员办Clay案
I'll tell Rawls you can keep two men for Clay.
其他就暂停了 直到有经费富裕
The rest is shut down until we can dig out.
我得走了
I got to run.
一个贪污的政客比22具尸体还重要
So one thieving politician trumps 22 dead bodies.
知道了
Good to know.
为了省钱 连警车都不上路
To save money, they're not even putting ops cars in the street.
取消两人一组的巡逻
No more two-man patrols.
老天 钱都上哪儿去了
Jesus, where did the money go?
学校
Schools.
Carcetti不想解雇老师  所以就拿我们开刀
Carcetti didn't want to lay off teachers, so he fucks us instead.
你似乎退出的是时候 对吧
Seems like you got out at the right time, huh?
看看你
Look at you.
咱的Thomas小子展示最新城中心商务装
Here's our boy Thomas sporting the latest in downtown businesswear,
低调地显摆一下
An understated ensemble that puts the "b" in subtle.
显摆还有低调的?
There's a "b" in subtle?
说真的 你看着不错 Herc
Seriously, you look well, Herc.
我生意很好
I'm doing good, man.
事情都干不完
I got more work than I can get to.
就像消息一传出去
It's like once word got around,
那些律师全找上门来了
these fucking lawyers came out of the fucking woodwork.
这倒让我想起来了  有个名字要你们帮着查查
Which reminds me, I need one of you guys to run a name for me.
车牌号 车证号 电话号码 查的时候顺便拍拍照片
Tags, registration, and phone. While you're at it, run a sheeting photo.
下一轮酒我来付 好吧
'Cause I'm buying the next round, right?
正是时候
About fucking time!
不习惯有钱呢 都忘了钱的样了
Not used to having money, you kind of forget.
咱再喝一轮
Let's get a round.
稿子怎么样
How does it read?
诚实尖锐
It's clean and it bites.
- 可以上头版 也许是第二条 - 我们怎么写
- Deserves a front, off-lead, maybe. - And we're saying what?
有重罪前科的脱衣舞俱乐部老板的 便宜买卖啊
That it's a sweetheart deal for a titty bar owner with a big criminal history.
他把现有的产业以120万卖给市政府
He sells his existing location to the city for 1.2 million
然后他们卖给他更好的产业
and they sell him a better piece of real estate
20万的价格 在五个街区外重建俱乐部
to relocate his club five blocks west for 200,000.
- 他就白挣了100万 - 拿什么补偿?
- He clears a million for laying in the cut. - What's the quid pro quo?
我们在查Nerese竞选委员会的捐赠人
We're going through donors in Nerese's  campaign committee, as we speak.
目前Ricardo Hendrix捐了4万
So far, we got 40,000 from Ricardo Hendrix
还有一群人 登记的地址都是这个俱乐部
and a bunch of people all using the same address as the bar.
这个怎么不在你的事先安排里?
Why wasn't this on your budget?
呃 我们发现... 其实是Jeff Price发现
Well, we found it... Actually, Jeff Price found it
这个藏在规划提案中 在议会议程的最后
hidden in the zoning bills, bottom of the council agenda.
发现得迟了 但还是发现了
He caught it late, but he caught it.
好吧 头版 中线下面
All right, front page, below the fold.
好
Yeah.
大都市部 Phelps
Metro desk, Phelps.
Gus  Price找你 二号线 他找到了Nerese
Gus, Price for you, line two, and he's got Nerese with him.
啊 好 来了
Aw, shit, here it comes.
- Gus? 我是Jeff - 嗯
- Gus? It's Jeff. - Year
议会主席想跟你说话
The council president would like a word with you.
- 公开的吗 - 不 她对我发表了看法
- On the record? - No. She's given me her quote.
- 她想跟你私下谈谈 - 接过来吧
- She wants to talk to you off the record. - Put her on.
这一切都是光明正大的
This is all perfectly above board.
毫无疑问 主席女士
No doubt, Madam President.
我们需要这地产用于重新发展
We need this property for redevelopment
允许Hendrix先生易地重建 都是为了城市着想
and it's in the city's interest to allow Mr. Hendrix to relocate.
给他两倍面积的地产 再给他100万解决问题
Is it in the city's interest to give him a property with twice as much floor space
符合市政利益吗
and give him a million dollars for his trouble?
你觉得你向议会说清楚了
Well, do you think you made it clear to the council
Hendrix先生向你的竞选委员会捐了6万了吗
that Mr. Hendrix donated $60,000 to your campaign committee?
我不知道 女士
I don't know, ma'am,
在我这里 6万可以买一堆善意呢
where I live, 60,000 buys a lot of goodwill.
嗨 Jeff 是你吗
Hey, Jeff, is that you?
我把你接给Spry
I'm putting you on hold for Spry.
对 把Nerese对你说的记录下来
Yeah, give me your on the record for Nerese.
- 准备好了吗 - 嗯
- Ready? - Yeah.
可惜她刚才说的不能登报
Shame we couldn't use what she just gave us.
什么发现
What do you got?
继续查竞选基金的事
Keep running through that campaign finance shit.
捐款里至少两万来历不明
There's at least $20,000 in contributions we haven't found yet.
Nerese基本上就算确认了
Nerese all but confirmed it.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
是我
It's me.
嗯 我们今晚会很晚
Yeah, we're going late tonight.
行
Fine.
不 没有
No, I'm not.
就是累了 没啥
I'm just tired, is all.
我累了说话就含糊
I slur when I'm tired.
就这样
That's all.
嗯
Yeah.
晚安
Night.
蓝盖 各种可卡因
Blue tops, all the rocks.
蓝盖 蓝盖
Blue tops. Blue tops.
蓝盖
Blue tops.
蓝盖 趁热买啊 来买蓝盖
Blue tops, get 'em while they hot. Come and get your blue tops.
Bubs 唷
Bubs, yo.
Hauk?
真是最后冒头的好消息
It was a great pull at deadline.
嗨 巴尔的摩政客管你叫混蛋 这样的夜晚都是美好的
Hey, any night a Baltimore politician calls you a son of a bitch is a good night.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
嗨 Alma干得好
Hey, that was a good pull by Alma,
最后拿到了大脸Rick的话
getting that quote from Fatface Rick for the home final.
"嗨 我是商人 市里想要帮我 我是不会拒绝的" 很好
"Hey, I'm a businessman. City wants to help me out, I ain't gonna argue." Sweet.
- 谢谢 - 你怎么让他开口的
- Thank you. - How'd you get him to talk to you?
我进去 然后坐下
I just walked in, sat down,
看了几分钟舞女 他就来搭讪了
watched the dancers for a few minutes, and he came over to me.
以为我要找工作
Thought I was looking for a job.
你这么干 不该只在鸣谢栏出现
You deserve more than a contributing line for that.
不知道 鸣谢栏也挺好的
I don't know, a contrib line is cool.
在鸣谢栏中 没多大前途
You can't go far on contrib lines.
你要去哪儿
Where do you want to go?
时报或是邮报 还能是哪儿呢
Times or Post. Where else?
不知道 这报纸还是挺好的
I don't know. This is still a pretty good paper.
我自己找了市长
I brought it to the mayor personally,
但他们的最后经费 都给了巡警和预防犯罪了
but they're throwing their last dollars into patrol and crime suppression.
你觉得一年来天天跟着Marlo和他的人
You think being on Marlo and his people every damn day for a year
就不是预防犯罪吗
isn't crime suppression?
压着这些人 就已经降低命案率了
We lowered the body count just by sitting on these people.
- 他们知道他们被调查吧 - 还用说 都一年了
- They know they're hot, huh? - After a year?
听着 我是得到了保证的
Look. Promises were made to me, as well.
他们告诉我 会有新的局面
I was told a new day was coming.
显然这不是新局面
Clearly, this isn't it.
我们要去哪儿呢
Where are we going, then?
你跟McNulty回凶案组
You and McNulty are back to the Homicide rotation.
Dozerman暂时派去战术组
Dozerman is temporarily assigned to tactical.
警督 你要去北边填补一个空缺 四到十二天轮一次岗
Lieutenant, you're going to fill a vacancy in the Northern, four to 12 shift.
Freamon Sydnor 你们俩去州检办公室
Freamon, Sydnor, you two are assigned to the state's attorney's office
协助完成Clay Davis提交大陪审团的事
to help grand-jury the Clay Davis thing.
等钱多了
When the money starts to flow,
我就把你们都弄回来
I'll get you all back on this somehow.
抱歉
Sorry.
真想知道在一个真正的警局工作的滋味
Wonder what it feels like to work in a real fucking police department.
50美分
50 cent.
谢谢
Obliged.
昨晚这是几点来的?
When did this break last night?
Gus大概九点半在议会计划中看到了
Gus saw it on the council agenda around 9:30.
真是好报道
It's a good fucking story.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey - Hey
相关回应报道谁负责
Who's doing the react piece?
Jeff 怎么了
Jeff will, why?
我就是...
I'm just...
我需要一个报道 我准备好了
I need a story. I'm up.
好啊 保持这种劲头
Yeah. Stay hungry like that.
好新闻自然会有的
Good things come when they come.
两点了 各位
It's two o'clock, people.
我需要新闻概要
I need budget lines.
这个城市里有上百万个故事
There are a million stories in the naked city,
但今天你们这些可怜的家伙 只需给我三四个就够了
but today you poor mooks only need to throw me three or four.
金莺队不买投手 我就不该离开Bronx (金莺队为巴尔的摩棒球队)
The Orioles will not pay for pitcher. I should have never left the Bronx.
- 看到了? - 什么
- You see this? - What?
咱们有个客户上头版了
One of our clients on the front page.
代表老虎伍兹?
Represent Tiger Woods?
只花一两轮酒钱就弄到了
All it cost me was a round of beers.
警局的人都喜欢我  我就是他妈的烈士
They fucking love me in the department. I'm a fucking martyr is what I am.
拦了一个黑人部长的车 惹毛了他
Pull over some black minister, piss him off,
我就丢了工作
and I lose my fucking job.
一轮酒?
One round?
你是个出色的辩方调查员
You, a prominent defense investigator,
试过让其他人买酒给你喝吗
let these other guys buy a round of drinks ever?
小子 你是该了解报销的规矩了
Kid, it's time you learned a little something about the expense account.
这是我的桌子
That's my desk.
你他妈的说啥呢
What the fuck you saying?
浪子回头啊
The prodigal son.